So we are going to have many quizzes throughout each unit.
The point of the quiz is to check that you understand what we have covered.
Some of the quizzes will be fairly straightforward just to see if you followed what we said.
Other quizzes will be more challenging and require you to put together several ideas that we have covered.
These quizzes don't count towards your grades. You will be able to try them as many times as you want until you hopefully get the answer right.
It certainly will be valuable to try to get the answer right the first time. But they shouldn't be stressful.
They are meant to keep you engaged in the lecture and to make sure you are understanding things.
After each quiz there will be an explanation and answer that often will go in more depth than just answering the quiz correctly.
So for the first quiz and to get started practicing quizzes our question is what is the goal of Unit 1?
So there are 4 choices: You can check all the choices that you think are good answers.
The first choice is that the goal is to get started programming.
The second choice is to learn some important computer science concepts.
The third choice is to write some code that extracts a link from a webpage.
The fourth choice is to write code to rank web pages.
So that is first quiz. Check as many answers as you think are correct.