If this is our hypothesis, we now must devise an experiment to further refine this hypothesis.
Let's come up with a very simple input where we'd assume that this quote.
If we put in just "foo" without any ten, we would assume that we would get the very same amount.
Let's do this as an experiment.
Here again, we have a buggy function  and now let's conduct the experiment.
So we invoke print html marker with "foo".
We press run and the output is foo without double quote.
So now we see the output. It's not what we expected.
The output will be foo without quote and this again confirm our hypothesis.
We can try this out with even more strength. Further strengthening our hypothesis.
So if we put in bar and very surprising it's going to happen.
We get bar as output and we put in just a two quotes.
what we get is an empty strength so we get more failures down the lane.
This hypothesis is confirmed now by a number of experiment
double quote our strip from tagged input, but actually we don't even have a new tag
so we can actually scratch that.
Double quote are stripped from general input.
So even if there's no tag these quotes are being stripped away.
Now we can actually go and explore the cause-effect chain.
If quotes have been stripped away, there must be a place in the code which doesn't.
The only place in our code where codes are handle right here in this line
and we have if there's a double quote or a single quote and tag is being set
then quote be inverted and when quote is inverted, tags should not be recognize.
Nothing to complicate but the why would the quote be script because normally we should not be in tag.
Maybe we are in tag. Maybe the variable tag is set.
So we can come up with a new hypothesis that explains precisely that.